const questions=[
    {
      question: "What is the full form of \\\"AI\\\"?",
      options: [
        "Artificially Intelligent",
        "Artificial Intelligence",
        "Artificially Intelligence",
        "Advanced Intelligence"
      ],
      answer: "Artificial Intelligence",
      explanation: "AI is abbreviated as Artificial Intelligence. It is used to create systems or build machines to think and work like humans."
    },
    {
      question: "What is Artificial Intelligence?",
      options: [
        "Artificial Intelligence is a field that aims to make humans more intelligent",
        "Artificial Intelligence is a field that aims to improve the security",
        "Artificial Intelligence is a field that aims to develop intelligent machines",
        "Artificial Intelligence is a field that aims to mine the data"
      ],
      answer: "Artificial Intelligence is a field that aims to develop intelligent machines",
      explanation: "Artificial Intelligence is the development of intelligent systems that work and react in the same way that humans do."
    },
    {
      question: "Who is the inventor of Artificial Intelligence?",
      options: [
        "Geoffrey Hinton",
        "Andrew Ng",
        "John McCarthy",
        "JÃ¼rgen Schmidhuber"
      ],
      answer: "John McCarthy",
      explanation: "John McCarthy was a pioneer in Artificial Intelligence research, helping to name the field and spending decades teaching computers to grasp concepts that are intuitive to humans."
    },
    {
      question: "Which of the following is the branch of Artificial Intelligence?",
      options: [
        "Machine Learning",
        "Cyber forensics",
        "Full-Stack Developer",
        "Network Design"
      ],
      answer: "Machine Learning",
      explanation: "Machine learning is one of the important sub-areas of Artificial Intelligence likewise Neural Networks, Computer Vision, Robotics, and NLP are also the sub-areas. In machine learning, we build or train ML models to do certain tasks."
    },
    {
      question: "What is the goal of Artificial Intelligence?",
      options: [
        "To solve artificial problems",
        "To extract scientific causes",
        "To explain various sorts of intelligence",
        "To solve real-world problems"
      ],
      answer: "To explain various sorts of intelligence",
      explanation: "Artificial Intelligence's goal is to explain various sorts of intelligence."
    },
     {
      question: "Which of the following is an application of Artificial Intelligence?",
      options: [
        "It helps to exploit vulnerabilities to secure the firm",
        "Language understanding and problem-solving (Text analytics and NLP)",
        "Easy to create a website",
        "It helps to deploy applications on the cloud"
      ],
      answer: "Language understanding and problem-solving (Text analytics and NLP)",
      explanation: "Language understanding and problem-solving come under the NLP and Text Analysis area which involves text recognition and sentiment analysis of the text. NLP ML model is trained to mainly do the task which processes human language's speech or text. For example voice assistant."
    },
    {
      question: "In how many categories process of Artificial Intelligence is categorized?",
      options: [
        "categorized into 5 categories",
        "processes are categorized based on the input provided",
        "categorized into 3 categories",
        "process is not categorized"
      ],
      answer: "categorized into 3 categories",
      explanation: "It is categorized into 3 steps Sensing, Reasoning, Acting i) Sensing: Through the sensor taking in the data about the world ii) Reasoning: Reasoning is thinking or processing the data sensed by the sensor. iii) Action: On the basis of input and reasoning, acting is generating and controlling actions in the environment."
    },
    {
      question: "Based on which of the following parameter Artificial Intelligence is categorized?",
      options: [
        "Based on functionally only",
        "Based on capabilities only",
        "Based on capabilities and functionally",
        "It is not categorized"
      ],
      answer: "Based on capabilities and functionally",
      explanation: "The two main categorizations of AI are based on the capability and functionality. Based on capability it is divided into Artificial Narrow Intelligence (ANI), Artificial General Intelligence (AGI), and Artificial Super Intelligence (ASI). Based on functionality it is divided into reactive machines, limited memory, theory of mind, and self-awareness."
    },
    {
      question: "Which of the following is a component of Artificial Intelligence?",
      options: [
        "Learning",
        "Training",
        "Designing",
        "Puzzling"
      ],
      answer: "Learning",
      explanation: "Intelligence is intangible and is composed of mainly five techniques. Learning is the process of gaining knowledge by understanding, practicing, being taught, or experiencing one thing. Learning enhances the awareness of any topic, hence learning is one of the important components."
    },
    {
      question: "What is the function of an Artificial Intelligence \"Agent\"?",
      options: [
        "Mapping of goal sequence to an action",
        "Work without the direct interference of the people",
        "Mapping of precept sequence to an action",
        "Mapping of environment sequence to an action"
      ],
      answer: "Mapping of precept sequence to an action",
      explanation: "A math function that converts a collection of perceptions into actions is known as the agent function. The function is implemented using agent software. An agent is responsible for the actions performed by the machine once it senses the environment."
    },
    {
      question: "Which of the following is not a type of Artificial Intelligence agent?",
      options: [
        "Learning Al agent",
        "Goal-based Al agent",
        "Simple reflex Al agent",
        "Unity-based Al agent"
      ],
      answer: "Unity-based Al agent",
      explanation: "There are mainly 5 types of agents:"
    },
     {
      question: "Which of the following is not the commonly used programming language for Artificial Intelligence?",
      options: [
        "Perl",
        "Java",
        "PROLOG",
        "LISP"
      ],
      answer: "Perl",
      explanation: "Perl is a scripting language. Whereas other programming languages are used to program Al machines."
    },
    {
      question: "What is the name of the Artificial Intelligence system developed by Daniel Bobrow?",
      options: [
        "program known as BACON",
        "system known as STUDENT",
        "program known as SHRDLU",
        "system known as SIMD"
      ],
      answer: "system known as STUDENT",
      explanation: "STUDENT is the name of the Artificial Intelligence system developed by Daniel Bobrow in 1964. Daniel Bobrow had used LISP programming language to write this Al program for his PhD thesis."
    },
    {
      question: "What is the function of the system Student?",
      options: [
        "program that can read algebra word problems only",
        "system which can solve algebra word problems but not read",
        "system which can read and solve algebra word problems",
        "None of the mentioned"
      ],
      answer: "system which can read and solve algebra word problems",
      explanation: "The system STUDENT developed by Daniel Bobrow was written in LISP to read and solve algebra word problems of high school books. This is referred as the achievement in the field of Natural Language Processing."
    },
    {
      question: "Which of the following is not an application of artificial intelligence?",
      options: [
        "Face recognition system",
        "Chatbots",
        "LIDAR",
        "DBMS"
      ],
      answer: "DBMS",
      explanation: "Face recognition system, Chatbots, and LIDAR are the various applications of Al in various fields like security system, business, automobiles etc. DBMS is used to store and manipulate data."
    },
    {
      question: "Which of the following machine requires input from the humans but can interpret the outputs themselves?",
      options: [
        "Actuators",
        "Sensor",
        "Agents",
        "AI system"
      ],
      answer: "AI system",
      explanation: "Actuators are used in machines to convert energy from one form to another to perform a physical function. The sensor is a device that receives signals from the physical environment to detect the changes. Systems receive input from humans and interpret the outputs."
    },
    {
      question: "number of informed search method are there in Artificial Intelligence.",
      options: [
        "4",
        "3",
        "2",
        "1"
      ],
      answer: "4",
      explanation: "There are four types of informed search methods. The four types of informed search method are best-first search, Greedy best-first search, A* search and memory bounded heuristic search."
    },
    {
      question: "The total number of proposition symbols in Al are",
      options: [
        "3 proposition symbols",
        "1 proposition symbols",
        "2 proposition symbols",
        "No proposition symbols"
      ],
      answer: "2 proposition symbols",
      explanation: "There are totally 2 proposition symbols. The two proposition symbols are true and false."
    },
    {
      question: "The total number of logical symbols in Al are",
      options: [
        "There are 3 logical symbols",
        "There are 5 logical symbols",
        "Number of logical symbols are based on the input",
        "Logical symbols are not used"
      ],
      answer: "There are 5 logical symbols",
      explanation: "There are totally five logical symbols. The five logical symbols are: a) Negation b) Conjunction c) Disjunction d) Implication e) Biconditional"
    },
    {
      question: "Which of the following are the approaches to Artificial Intelligence?",
      options: [
        "Applied approach",
        "Strong approach",
        "Weak approach",
        "All of the mentioned"
      ],
      answer: "All of the mentioned",
      explanation: "Strong AI is used to build machines that can truly reason and solve problems. Weak AI deals with building computer-based Artificial Intelligence that can act as if it were intelligent but cannot truly reason and solve problems. Applied approach creates commercially viable \"smart\" systems. In the Cognitive approach, a computer is used to test theories about how the human mind works."
    },
    {
      question: "Face Recognition system is based on which type of approach?",
      options: [
        "Weak AI approach",
        "Applied Al approach",
        "Cognitive Al approach",
        "Strong Al approach"
      ],
      answer: "Applied Al approach",
      explanation: "Applied approach aims to produce commercially viable \"smart\" systems such as, for example, a security system that recognizes the faces of people to provide access. The applied approach has already enjoyed considerable success."
    },
    {
      question: "Which of the following is an advantage of artificial intelligence?",
      options: [
        "Reduces the time taken to solve the problem",
        "Helps in providing security",
        "Have the ability to think hence makes the work easier",
        "All of the above"
      ],
      answer: "All of the above",
      explanation: "Artificial intelligence creates a machine that can think and make decisions without human involvement."
    },
    {
      question: "Which of the following can improve the performance of an Al agent?",
      options: [
        "Perceiving",
        "Learning",
        "Observing",
        "All of the mentioned"
      ],
      answer: "Learning",
      explanation: "An Al agent learns from previous states by saving it and responding to the same situation better if it occurs again in the future. Hence, learning can improve the performance of an Al agent."
    },
    {
      question: "Which of the following is/are the composition for Al agents?",
      options: [
        "Program only",
        "Architecture only",
        "Both Program and Architecture",
        "None of the mentioned"
      ],
      answer: "Both Program and Architecture",
      explanation: "An Al agent program will implement function mapping percepts to actions."
    },
    {
      question: "On which of the following approach A basic line following robot is based?",
      options: [
        "Applied approach",
        "Weak approach",
        "Strong approach",
        "Cognitive approach"
      ],
      answer: "Weak approach",
      explanation: "Weak approach is concerned with the development of a computer-based artificial intelligence that can behave intelligently but cannot really reason or solve issues. According to Weak approach, properly configured computers can mimic human intellect."
    },
    {
      question: "Artificial Intelligence has evolved extremely in all the fields except for",
      options: [
        "Web mining",
        "Construction of plans in real time dynamic systems",
        "Understanding natural language robustly",
        "All of the mentioned"
      ],
      answer: "All of the mentioned",
      explanation: "Artificial Intelligence is used in all the fields to make work easier and complete the work before the deadline. However, it could not excel in these fields. Hence, these areas need more focus for improvements."
    },
    {
      question: "Which of the following is an example of artificial intelligent agent/agents?",
      options: [
        "Autonomous Spacecraft",
        "Human",
        "Robot",
        "All of the mentioned"
      ],
      answer: "All of the mentioned",
      explanation: "Humans can be considered agents. Sensors include eyes, ears, skin, taste buds, and so on, whereas effectors include hands, fingers, legs, and mouth. Agents are robots. Sensors on robots might include a camera, sonar, infrared, bumper, and so on. Actuators can include grippers, wheels, lights, speakers, and other components. Based on its senses, autonomous spacecraft makes decisions on its own."
    },
    {
      question: "Which of the following is an expansion of Artificial Intelligence application?",
      options: [
        "Game Playing",
        "Planning and Scheduling",
        "Diagnosis",
        "All of the mentioned"
      ],
      answer: "All of the mentioned",
      explanation: "In recent days Al is used in all sectors in different forms. All sectors require intelligence and automation for its working."
    },
    {
      question: "What is an Al 'agent'?",
      options: [
        "Takes input from the surroundings and uses its intelligence and performs the desired operations",
        "An embedded program controlling line following robot",
        "Perceives its environment through sensors and acting upon that environment through actuators",
        "All of the mentioned"
      ],
      answer: "All of the mentioned",
      explanation: "An Al agent is defined as anything that uses sensors and actuators to perceive and act on the environment. It receives information from its surroundings via sensors, executes operations, and outputs via actuators."
    },
    {
      question: "Which of the following environment is strategic?",
      options: [
        "Rational",
        "Deterministic",
        "Partial",
        "Stochastic"
      ],
      answer: "Deterministic",
      explanation: "In a deterministic environment the output is determined based on a particular state. If the environment is deterministic except for the action of other agents it is called deterministic."
    },
    {
      question: "What is the name of Artificial Intelligence which allows machines to handle vague information with a deftness that mimics human intuition?",
      options: [
        "Human intelligence",
        "Boolean logic",
        "Functional logic",
        "Fuzzy logic"
      ],
      answer: "Fuzzy logic",
      explanation: "Many popular goods, such as microwave ovens, cars, and plug-in circuit boards for desktop PCs, employ the first widely-used commercial form of Artificial Intelligence. It enables robots to handle ambiguous data with a dexterity that resembles human intuition."
    },
    {
      question: "Which of the following produces hypotheses that are easy to read for humans?",
      options: [
        "Machine Learning",
        "ILP",
        "First-order logic",
        "Propositional logic"
      ],
      answer: "ILP",
      explanation: "ILP (Inductive logic programming) is a subfield of artificial intelligence. Because ILP can participate in the scientific cycle of experimentation So that it can produce a flexible structure."
    },
    {
      question: "What does the Bayesian network provide?",
      options: [
        "Partial description of the domain",
        "Complete description of the problem",
        "Complete description of the domain",
        "None of the mentioned"
      ],
      answer: "Complete description of the domain",
      explanation: "A Bayesian network provides a complete description of the domain."
    },
    {
     question: "What is the total number of quantification available in artificial intelligence?",
      options: [
        "4",
        "3",
        "1",
        "2"
      ],
      answer: "2",
      explanation: "There are two types of quantification. They are: a) Universal b) Existential"
    },
    {
      question: "What is Weak AI?",
      options: [
        "the study of mental faculties using mental models implemented on a computer",
        "the embodiment of human intellectual capabilities within a computer",
        "a set of computer programs that produce output that would be considered to reflect intelligence if it were generated by humans",
        "all of the mentioned"
      ],
      answer: "the study of mental faculties using mental models implemented on a computer",
      explanation: "Weak AI is the study of mental faculties using mental models implemented on a computer."
    },
    {
      question: "Which of the following are the 5 big ideas of AI?",
      options: [
        "Perception",
        "Human-AI Interaction",
        "Societal Impact",
        "All of the above"
      ],
      answer: "Allof the above",
      explanation: "The 5 big ideas are: 1. Which instruments are used for perceiving and acting upon the environment?"
    },
    {
      question: "Which instruments are used for perceiving and acting upon the environment?",
      options: [
        "Sensors and Actuators",
        "Sensors",
        "Perceiver",
        "None of the mentioned"
      ],
      answer: "Sensors and Actuators",
      explanation: "An agent is anything that can be viewed as perceiving and acting upon the environment through the sensors and actuators."
    },
    {
      question: "What is meant by agentâs percept sequence?",
      options: [
        "Used to perceive the environment",
        "Complete history of actuator",
        "Complete history of perceived things",
        "None of the mentioned"
      ],
      answer: "Complete history of perceived things",
      explanation: "An agentâs percept sequence is the complete history of everything that the agent has ever perceived."
    },
    {
      question: "How many types of agents are there in artificial intelligence?",
      options: [
        "1",
        "2",
        "3",
        "4"
      ],
      answer: "4",
      explanation: "The four types of agents are Simple reflex, Model based, Goal based and Utility based agents."
    },
    {
      question: "What is the rule of simple reflex agent?",
      options: [
        "Simple-action rule",
        "Condition-action rule",
        "Simple & Condition-action rule",
        "None of the mentioned"
      ],
      answer: "Condition-action rule",
      explanation: "Simple reflex agent is based on the present condition and so it is condition action rule."
    },
    {
      question: "What are the composition for agents in artificial intelligence?",
      options: [
        "Program",
        "Architecture",
        "Both Program & Architecture",
        "None of the mentioned"
      ],
      answer: "Both Program & Architecture",
      explanation: "An agent program will implement function mapping percepts to actions."
    },
    {
      question: "In which agent does the problem generator is present?",
      options: [
        "Learning agent",
        "Observing agent",
        "Reflex agent",
        "None of the mentioned"
      ],
      answer: "Learning agent",
      explanation: "Problem generator will give the suggestion to improve the output for learning agent."
    },
    {
      question: "Which is used to improve the agents performance?",
      options: [
        "Perceiving",
        "Learning",
        "Observing",
        "None of the mentioned"
      ],
      answer: "Learning",
      explanation: "An agent can improve its performance by storing its previous actions."
    },
    {
      question: "Which agent deals with happy and unhappy states?",
      options: [
        "Simple reflex agent",
        "Model based agent",
        "Learning agent",
        "Utility based agent"
      ],
      answer: "Utility based agent",
      explanation: "A utility function maps a state onto a real number which describes the associated degree of happiness."
    },
    {
      question: "Which action sequences are used to achieve the agentâs goal?",
      options: [
        "Search",
        "Plan",
        "Retrieve",
        "Both Search & Plan"
      ],
      answer: "Both Search & Plan",
      explanation: "When the environment becomes more tricky means, the agent needs plan and search action sequence to achieve the goal."
    },
    {
      question: "Which element in the agent are used for selecting external actions?",
      options: [
        "Perceive",
        "Performance",
        "Learning",
        "Actuator"
      ],
      answer: "Performance",
      explanation: "None."
    },
    {
      question: "What is the main task of a problem-solving agent?",
      options: [
        "Solve the given problem and reach to goal",
        "To find out which sequence of action will get it to the goal state",
        "All of the mentioned",
        "None of the mentioned"
      ],
      answer: "All of the mentioned",
      explanation: "The problem-solving agents are one of the goal-based agents."
    },
    {
      question: "What is state space?",
      options: [
        "The whole problem",
        "Your Definition to a problem",
        "Problem you design",
        "Representing your problem with variable and parameter"
      ],
      answer: "Representing your problem with variable and parameter",
      explanation: "Because state space is mostly concerned with a problem, when you try to solve a problem, we have to design a mathematical structure to the problem, which can only be through variables and parameters. eg. You have given a 4-gallon jug and another 3-gallon jug. Neither has measuring marker on it. You have to fill the jugs with water. How can you get exactly 2 gallons of water in to 4 gallons. Here the state space can defined as set of ordered pairs integers(x,y), such that x=0,1,2,3 or 4 and y=0,1,2 or 3; X represents the number of gallons in 4 gallon jug and y represents the quantity of water in the 3-gallon jug."
    },
    {
      question: "The problem-solving agent with several immediate options of unknown value can decide what to do by just examining different possible sequences of actions that lead to states of known value, and then choosing the best sequence. This process of looking for such a sequence is called Search.",
      options: [
        "True",
        "False"
      ],
      answer: "True",
      explanation: "Refer to the definition of problem-solving agent."
    },
    {
      question: "A search algorithm takes _________ as an input and returns ________ as an output.",
      options: [
        "Input, output",
        "Problem, solution",
        "Solution, problem",
        "Parameters, sequence of actions"
      ],
      answer: "Problem, solution",
      explanation: "A search algorithm takes input as a problem and returns a solution to the problem as an output."
    },
    {
      question: "A problem in a search space is defined by one of these state.",
      options: [
        "Initial state",
        "Last state",
        "Intermediate state",
        "All of the mentioned"
      ],
      answer: "Initial state",
      explanation: "A problem has four components initial state, goal test, set of actions, path cost."
    },
    {
      question: "The Set of actions for a problem in a state space is formulated by a ___________",
      options: [
        "Intermediate states",
        "Initial state",
        "Successor function, which takes current action and returns next immediate state",
        "None of the mentioned"
      ],
      answer: "Successor function, which takes current action and returns next immediate state",
      explanation: "The most common formulation for actions uses a successor function. Given a particular state x, SUCCESSOR-FN(x) returns a set of (action, successor) ordered pairs, where each action is one of the legal actions in state x and each successor is a state that can be reached from x by applying the action."
    },
    {
      question: "A solution to a problem is a path from the initial state to a goal state. Solution quality is measured by the path cost function, and an optimal solution has the highest path cost among all solutions.",
      options: [
        "True",
        "False"
      ],
      answer: "False",
      explanation: "A solution to a problem is a path from the initial state to a goal state. Solution quality is measured by the path cost function, and an optimal solution has the lowest path cost among all solutions."
    },
    {
      question: "The process of removing detail from a given state representation is called ______",
      options: [
        "Extraction",
        "Abstraction",
        "Information Retrieval",
        "Mining of data"
      ],
      answer: "Abstraction",
      explanation: "The process of removing detail from a representation is called abstraction."
    },
    {
      question: "A problem solving approach works well for ______________",
      options: [
        "8-Puzzle problem",
        "8-queen problem",
        "Finding a optimal path from a given source to a destination",
        "Mars Hover (Robot Navigation)"
      ],
      answer: "Mars Hover (Robot Navigation)",
      explanation: "Problem-solving approach works well for toy problems and real-world problems."
    },
    {
      question: "The _______ is a touring problem in which each city must be visited exactly once. The aim is to find the shortest tour.",
      options: [
        "Finding shortest path between a source and a destination",
        "Travelling Salesman problem",
        "Map coloring problem",
        "Depth first search traversal on a given map represented as a graph"
      ],
      answer: "Travelling Salesman problem",
      explanation: "Refer the TSP problem."
    },
    {
      question: "Web Crawler is a/an ____________",
      options: [
        "Intelligent goal-based agent",
        "Problem-solving agent",
        "Simple reflex agent",
        "Model based agent"
      ],
      answer: "Intelligent goal-based agent",
      explanation: "Web Crawling is type of search for a relevant document from given seed documents. Focused crawlers exists, helps to improvise the search efficiency."
    },
    {
      question: "What is the major component/components for measuring the performance of problem solving?",
      options: [
        "Completeness",
        "Optimality",
        "Time and Space complexity",
        "All of the mentioned"
      ],
      answer: "All of the mentioned",
      explanation: "For best performance consideration of all component is necessary."
    },
    {
      question: "A production rule consists of ____________",
      options: [
        "A set of Rule",
        "A sequence of steps",
        "Set of Rule & sequence of steps",
        "Arbitrary representation to problem"
      ],
      answer: "Set of Rule & sequence of steps",
      explanation: "When you are trying to solve a problem, you should design how to get a step-by-step solution with constraints condition to your problem, e.g Chess board problem."
    },
    {
      question: "Which search method takes less memory?",
      options: [
        "Depth-First Search",
        "Breadth-First search",
        "Linear Search",
        "Optimal search"
      ],
      answer: "Depth-First Search",
      explanation: "Depth-First Search takes less memory since only the nodes on the current path are stored, but in Breadth First Search, all of the tree that has generated must be stored."
    },
    {
      question: "Which is the best way to go for Game playing problem?",
      options: [
        "Linear approach",
        "Heuristic approach (Some knowledge is stored)",
        "Random approach",
        "An Optimal approach"
      ],
      answer: "Heuristic approach (Some knowledge is stored)",
      explanation: "We use a Heuristic approach, as it will find out brute force computation, looking at hundreds of thousands of positions. e.g Chess competition between Human and AI based Computer."
    },
    {
      question: "What is a Cybernetics?",
      options: [
        "Study of communication between two machines",
        "Study of communication between human and machine",
        "Study of communication between two humans",
        "Study of Boolean values"
      ],
      answer: "Study of communication between human and machine",
      explanation: "Cybernetics is Study of communication between human and machine."
    },
    {
      question: "What is the goal of artificial intelligence?",
      options: [
        "To solve real-world problems",
        "To solve artificial problems",
        "To explain various sorts of intelligence",
        "To extract scientific causes"
      ],
      answer: "To explain various sorts of intelligence",
      explanation: "The scientific goal of artificial intelligence is to explain various sorts of intelligence."
    },
    {
      question: "An algorithm is complete if ____________",
      options: [
        "It terminates with a solution when one exists",
        "It starts with a solution",
        "It does not terminate with a solution",
        "It has a loop"
      ],
      answer: "It terminates with a solution when one exists",
      explanation: "An Algorithm is complete if It terminates with a solution when one exists."
    },
    {
      question: "Which is true regarding BFS (Breadth First Search)?",
      options: [
        "BFS will get trapped exploring a single path",
        "The entire tree so far been generated must be stored in BFS",
        "BFS is not guaranteed to find a solution if exists",
        "BFS is nothing but Binary First Search"
      ],
      answer: "The entire tree so far been generated must be stored in BFS",
      explanation: "Regarding BFS-The entire tree so far been generated must be stored in BFS."
    },
    {
      question: "What is a heuristic function?",
      options: [
        "A function to solve mathematical problems",
        "A function which takes parameters of type string and returns an integer value",
        "A function whose return type is nothing",
        "A function that maps from problem state descriptions to measures of desirability"
      ],
      answer: "A function that maps from problem state descriptions to measures of desirability",
      explanation: "Heuristic function is a function that maps from problem state descriptions to measures of desirability."
    },
    {
      question: "The traveling salesman problem involves n cities with paths connecting the cities. The time taken for traversing through all the cities, without knowing in advance the length of a minimum tour, is ___________",
      options: [
        "O(n)",
        "O(n2)",
        "O(n!)",
        "O(n/2)"
      ],
      answer: "O(n!)",
      explanation: "The traveling salesman problem involves n cities with paths connecting the cities. The time taken for traversing through all the cities, without knowing in advance the length of a minimum tour, is O(n!)."
    },
    {
      question: "What is the problem space of means-end analysis?",
      options: [
        "An initial state and one or more goal states",
        "One or more initial states and one goal state",
        "One or more initial states and one or more goal state",
        "One initial state and one goal state"
      ],
      answer: "An initial state and one or more goal states",
      explanation: "The problem space of means-end analysis has an initial state and one or more goal states."
    },
    {
      question: "An algorithm A is admissible if ___________",
      options: [
        "It is not guaranteed to return an optimal solution when one exists",
        "It is guaranteed to return an optimal solution when one exists",
        "It returns more solutions, but not an optimal one",
        "It guarantees to return more optimal solutions"
      ],
      answer: "It is guaranteed to return an optimal solution when one exists",
      explanation: "An algorithm A is admissible if It is guaranteed to return an optimal solution when one exists."
    },
    {
      question: "Knowledge may be I. Declarative. II. Procedural. III. Non-procedural.",
      options: [
        "Only (I)",
        "Only (II)",
        "Only (III)",
        "Both (I) and (II)"
      ],
      answer: "Both (I) and (II)",
      explanation: "Knowledge may be declarative and procedural."
    },
    {
      question: "Idempotency law is I. P Ã P = P. II. P Ã P = P. III. P + P = P.",
      options: [
        "Only (I)",
        "Only (II)",
        "Only (III)",
        "Both (I) and (II)"
      ],
      answer: "Only (I)",
      explanation: "Idempotency Law is P V P = P."
    }
  ]